You continue searching to the north.
Make sure to search thoroughly.
- Yes!
As for His Majesty
and the Empress Dowager,
make sure they are strictly guarded.
Report immediately
if there's anything unusual.
- Yes!
You guys, come with me.
- Crown Prince!
Crown Prince!
All available men have been dispatched.
The garrisoned guards nearby
are also rushing here.
Crown Prince!
You've been keeping watch
for most of the night.
The night is cold and damp.
You should go back and rest for a while.
The mountains here stretch on endlessly,
and the terrain is complex.
The enemy deliberately struck here,
knowing it would be hard to search.
Searching the mountain inch by inch
is like looking for a needle
in a haystack.
I will stay right here.
Mo Yuan can report to me at any time.
I want to see the Crown Prince
return safely.
Crown Prince!
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 30=
You're not pretending anymore?
What are you talking about, Changqing?
My body is weak.
You can't just leave me behind.
I must say, all these years,
you've really put on a good act.
If I didn't pretend,
how could I experience
this rare brotherly bond?
Don't run!
Stop right there!
- What happened to the brotherly bond?
- Stop!
- After them!
Wait for me!
Get them!
Hurry!
Chase them!
After them!
Get them!
Search carefully!
You guys, go that way.
- Yes!
Search thoroughly!
This way!
Over there!
Stop!
After them!
Don't run!
They're over there!
Stop!
That way!
Get them!
After them!
That way!
Changqing,
keep going down this path,
and you'll be able
to leave this mountain.
What about you?
You're injured.
I'll stay behind to hold them off.
No.
If we leave, we'll leave together.
I don't want to owe you a favor.
Aren't you best at saving your own skin?
If you don't go back for reinforcements,
neither of us will make it out.
Tell Xihe not to worry
and wait for my return.
Go.
Come back.
Crown Prince!
Your Highness,
we still haven't found any trace
of Prince Xin and the Crown Prince
in the east.
Send another squad
to search deeper into the west.
Yes.
Somebody, come quick.
Your Highnesses,
Prince Xin has returned.
Crown Prince!
Let me.
Changqing,
are you badly hurt?
It's nothing serious.
Prince Xin,
why didn't the Crown Prince return
with you?
Where is he?
Crown Prince and I were trapped
in a cave.
We encountered a large group of pursuers
while escaping.
To cover my escape,
Crown Prince stayed behind alone
to hold them off.
Was he injured?
At least when I left,
he was fine.
He also said
to tell you not to worry.
Let's go rescue him quickly.
Follow me.
Mo Yuan.
Changqing.
Crown Prince,
I finally managed to invite you here.
Since my forth brother invited me,
how could I not come?
You knew it was me all along.
The people who besieged Changqing and me
were highly skilled.
They were definitely
not ordinary soldiers.
But they tied me up and didn't kill me.
Right now,
the only person who doesn't want me dead
yet is my sworn enemy
is none other than you.
You also know
that after that incident in northwest,
you have no chance
at the throne anymore.
So I guessed
that you must have
some unfinished business
and wanted to clear things up
with me face to face.
Huayong,
I truly admire your intellect
and respect your methods.
Come to think of it,
the biggest mistake I made
was from the very beginning
going against you.
But don't worry,
today,
I'm not here to hurt you.
I just want
to make a deal
with you.
What kind of deal?
Haven't you always wanted to know
who poisoned you?
I can tell you the truth right now.
But my condition
is to clear Yanyan of all her crimes,
and allow her to be buried
with the honors of a Princess Consort
in the imperial mausoleum,
and receive ancestral offerings.
As long as you agree,
it can be done.
Back then, Father
arranged my marriage to the princess
of the fallen Nanzhou state.
He used my marriage
to show his benevolence,
but it also ruined my path
to becoming the Crown Prince.
Later, Yanyan and I fell in love.
I thought
we could grow old together.
I didn't expect Father
to actually reprimand me,
saying I was supposed to monitor her,
not fall in love with her.
It's truly ridiculous.
My future,
my feelings,
to him,
are nothing
but stepping stones to the throne.
From childhood to adulthood,
when has he ever treated me
like his own son?
How could I not hate him?
But Yanyan was always innocent.
She was always coerced by me,
taking the blame for me,
and doing many things against her will.
The person I've let down the most
in this life
is her.
Li Yanhui was deeply devoted.
As for burying her
in the imperial mausoleum,
I can promise you.
Then, thank you, Huayong,
for fulfilling my long-cherished wish.
But I don't need you
to negotiate terms with me.
I want you to return to the palace
and plead guilty to Father.
Plead guilty?
Huayong,
do you think our father
is some kind of honorable gentleman?
Did you know
that Prince Qian treated him
like a blood brother,
yet he, on the battlefield,
brutally murdered his older brother
to usurp the throne?
Xiao Changtai,
stop your nonsense!
Actually, you and I are the same.
We are just pitiful people
used by Father
and then abandoned.
I can tell you the truth right now.
The one who poisoned you back then,
leaving you bedridden
and doomed to an early death,
is none other
than our good father!
Xiao Changtai,
I've long heard
these rumors you speak of.
Don't seek revenge on the wrong person.
But don't delude yourself into thinking
you can drive a wedge
between Father and me with this.
Once you see this,
you'll have no choice but to believe it.
(Year 8 of Youning, Daxing.)
(Year 8 of Youning)
(I'm here to confess to all ancestors.)
(Tablet of Prince Qian, Xiao Juewei)
(My sins burden the state,)
(causing the royal family
to lose its virtue.)
(Emperor Youning, Xiao Juechong, plotted
to murder his own brother, Prince Qian.)
(Fearing chaos would ruin the country,
I helped him hide his crime,)
(letting his sibling's blood be shed.)
(Edict of Repentance)
(This is my first sin.)
(Later, I learned he secretly
harmed his own son, Xiao Huayong.)
(But I dared not expose it.)
(Though I sheltered
the young child from disaster,)
(Tablet of Prince Qian, Xiao Juewei)
(I still cannot escape the blame.)
(This is my second sin.)
(Meng Weeps Blood and Kowtows)
(I received the ancestors' protection,)
(yet I indulged my son in doing evil,
violating morality and heaven.)
(Today, I bare my heart
with this edict of repentance,)
(praying to the heavens)
(Edict of Repentance)
(to bless Daxing with order and peace.)
Back then, Father murdered Prince Qian.
If this matter were exposed,
the various factions
would be unrestrained.
Perhaps they would raise their
own armies and divide the empire.
Grandmother either had
to join him in death,
or cover for him
to ensure his ascension to the throne.
She had no choice at the time.
Out of helplessness,
Grandmother covered up
all of Father's sins.
On this edict of repentance,
every word is written
with a bleeding heart.
It's written clearly.
Even if you don't believe my words,
you must know full well
whether this handwriting is that
of Grandmother herself.
Why did Father want to kill me?
Why bother racking your brains over it?
I will let you go.
You can ask him yourself.
Wouldn't that be better?
But sometimes,
I truly don't understand.
Why would a sickly person like me
receive such generous treatment
and care from you?
Whoever fed you the cherry cheese
is the one who poisoned you.
A word of advice for you.
Don't put too much trust
in your father.
In his heart,
there is only the throne.
There is no father and son.
- Crown Prince!
- Where are you, Crown Prince?
Crown Princess,
it's getting late,
and the paths
are becoming harder to navigate.
Let me have someone
escort you back first.
We've got it from here.
Until I find the Crown Prince,
I absolutely will not go back.
- Crown Prince!
Hurry!
Let's go!
- Crown Prince!
Crown Prince!
Crown Prince, where are you?
- Crown Prince!
Slender-Leaf Qionghua.
Moonlit Cool Fragrance.
- Crown Prince!
♪As time rushes by,
spring brings life, autumn brings death♪
♪A heart weathered by frost
will melt in love♪
♪Across miles of treasured moments,
every move is a game of truth and lies♪
♪With this broken body,
I'll become your armor♪
♪I want destiny,
and also tender words of love♪
♪As night stains my eyes,
I'll gaze once more at the rosy clouds♪
Let's go.
Mo Yuan.
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level♪
Let me look at you.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
I'm perfectly fine.
I'm not hurt at all.
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
Why did they let you go?
♪I have a dream of a long wind
in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level♪
Changtai let me out.
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
Let's go home first.
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
Your Highness!
♪May the sand and dirt in my sleeves♪
♪Become the tears
in the corner of my eyes♪
♪And blossom into a flower♪
(Clarity and Serenity)
Hurry up.
Hurry.
Your Majesty, Xiao Changtai has fled
into the deep mountains.
We've lost his trail.
His whereabouts are unknown.
Keep searching.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
the poison in the Crown Prince
has flared up again.
It's very aggressive.
Much more severe than before.
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Your Highness.
Xihe.
I'm here.
I'm right here.
Xihe.
Huayong, come.
What's wrong?
- Your Highness!
Call the imperial physician!
- Huayong.
- Call the imperial physician!
- Huayong!
- Your Highness!
Father.
I don't believe it.
Don't be afraid.
It was just a dream.
Your Highness,
you're awake.
Xihe,
you've been with me this whole time?
This is the medicine made
from the Slender-Leaf Qionghua?
Your Highness,
while I was watching over you,
I kept thinking
that when you woke up,
there was something I must tell you.
What is it?
No matter the dangers ahead,
I will stay by your side
and press forward with you.
In my heart,
you are the best.
With you here,
my heart has found its home.
(Chenning Hall)
(Why did Father want to kill me?)
Why bother racking your brains over it?
I will let you go.
(You can ask him yourself.)
(Wouldn't that be better?)
Your Majesty, time for your medicine.
Greetings, Father.
Huayong...
My boy is back.
Your Majesty.
What's wrong with His Majesty?
Your Highness,
after you went missing,
His Majesty worried day and night,
and caught a cold.
Come.
Huayong,
let me take a good look at you.
Quick, tell me,
how did you get back?
I caught them off guard
and escaped on my own.
Good.
That's good.
Seeing my boy,
my illness
is more than half cured.
Be good, Huayong.
Drink your medicine.
You'll slowly get better.
Come.
Father, it's broken.
Let me see.
Let me take a look.
It's cracked.
As long as we repair it with care,
it can be fixed.
Father.
You're awake.
Huayong,
I've fixed this box.
From now on, use it
to hold your favorite candies.
Thank you, Father.
This is what I
used as a child.
I can't believe you kept it
all this time.
Inside are
my favorite honey candies
from childhood.
Huayong,
you've suffered.
Your body is still weak.
Don't worry about me.
Hurry back to your palace and rest.
Get up.
Go back.
Let me help you lie down.
I will take my leave.
Let's go back.
(East Palace)
It's late and the dew is heavy.
Why are you still out here in the wind?
You haven't rested yet?
I'm waiting for you.
You went to see His Majesty today.
Was it about
what the Fourth Prince said?
He was desperate and talking nonsense.
How could it be taken seriously?
Father has ordered
a strict manhunt across the country.
Father and I
have never had a rift.
And we never will.
If you want to be alone for a while,
I'll go back and wait for you.
Stay with me.
Just for a little while.
Okay.
I'll stay with you.
But...
not here.
Your Highness,
the scented bath is ready.
You may leave.
Understood.
Your Highness,
go change your clothes first.
♪Amidst the flickering lights♪
♪Alone for several autumns♪
This scented bath is indeed different.
Just the smell of it is refreshing.
In this bath,
I used roselle, sour jujube seed,
and silktree bark.
They are all herbs
that calm the mind
and soothe the nerves.
♪For all eternity♪
♪The timeless wind and moon♪
♪Quietly reflect in your sparkling eyes♪
♪Scattered red petals fall like rain♪
♪It's a wonderful time in the world♪
♪Bits of worries and sorrows♪
Is the water temperature okay?
It's perfect.
Are you still tired?
With you here,
everything is alright.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
The Crown Princess is pregnant.
We're having a baby.
(Three years old, four years old)
If there is truly a way
(Fourteen years old)
to let me stay with her a little longer,
even if it means enduring the agony
of reforging my body,
I am willing to do it.
Tell me the truth.
Am I already beyond cure?
♪How can you be this wonderful♪
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)